so that brings us to a so-called
tournament predictor the idea is that
you have two predictors one is better
for some branches the other is better
for other branches now what you want to
do is to get the best behavior for all
types of branches so what you want to do
is when you have these branches use the
first predictor when you have these
branches use the second predictor but
you don't know which branches are going
to benefit from which of your two
predictors ahead of time so what you
really have is your two predictors let's
say that they're G share and pshare you
will use your PC of the branch to index
into both of the predictors you will
take the decisions that they generate
and now you need to decide which one to
use how do you do that and the idea of a
tournament predictor is to use a
so-called meta predictor which is just
an array of two bit counters you also
use the PC2 index there and the entry of
the meta
predictor does not tell you a prediction
for the branch it tells you
which of the two predictors is the more
likely to give an accurate prediction
for that Branch so what you do is you
use this to choose among the two
decisions so pretty much this meta
predictor gives you a way to select
among the two decisions so that the
final outcome is the decision that the
meta predictor thinks is a better
prediction you train the individual
predictors just like before on every
Branch outcome you train each of the
predictors you train The Meta predictor
a little bit differently instead of
counting up when taken and counting down
when not taken the meta predictor is
instead trained on how well these two
are doing if your two predictors are
both correct then your meta predictor
doesn't change anything if your first
predictor like in this case your gshare
is correct but the other one is not then
you count down counting down will result
in selecting the gshare result more
often if your first predictor is wrong
but your second predictor is right then
you count up counting up will result in
choosing this prediction more often and
finally if both of them are wrong then
the meta predictor doesn't change
because again there is no benefit in
trying to select one over the other so
the idea of the meta predictor is that
the prediction bit of the 2bit counter
is telling you really which of these to
select the hysteresis is there just in
case gshare is overall the more accurate
but sometimes pshare beats it or the
other way around and again each branch
has its own meta predictor entry so this
type of decision and this type of
selection is done dependent on branches
so pretty much for your for example Loop
exit Branch it might be that the pshare
works better for your correlated
branches it might be that the G share
works works better and they will have
different meta predictor entries so that
they will use different predictors for
their outcomes